Tom Power Creative Developer

Tom Power

Johan Huizingalaan 397 Amsterdam, 1066 TX

+353 86 3439838

tom@wildsurmisemusic.com

Websites:

tothepoweroftom.github.io tothepoweroftom.com

Skills

My current focus is on web development, (Vuejs, Threejs, p5js, Tonejs) but I'm also proficient in iOS development in Swift. My scientific background lends itself to C++ and Python. My music background lends itself to PureData, Max/MSP and Csound. Recently my focus has been on using recent developments in Machine Learning, such as using LSTM's to generate poetry and using Posenet as a Microsoft Kinect replacement in interactive installations. And also exploring Javascript as a creative coding medium.

Experience

Imagination Of Things - Lead Creative Technologist

January 2019 - Present, Amsterdam, Netherlands

http://imaginationofthings.com/

I work as lead creative technologist with Imagination of Things. Working on client projects for large and small companies around the Netherlands.

Blocksmith Fund - Technology Consultant

January 2019 - Present, London, UK

http://www.blocksmithfund.com/

I freelance for Blocksmith Fund as a machine learning and software development consultant. The company aims to provide data-based insights for investors in cryptocurrencies. I assist with research and software development for the platform.

MOBGEN:Lab - Creative Technologist

October 2016 - May 2019, Amsterdam, Netherlands https://www.mobgen.com/

I worked for 30 months with MOBGEN:Lab, a innovation lab within Accenture Netherlands. A mixture between client MVP projects and internal research projects. Projects ranged from skills for Google Home, iOS AR applications, interactive installations and websites.

Birdy Back - Freelance iOS Developer

September 2018 - December 2018, Dublin, Ireland

My brother Sean Power has his own Enterprise Ireland funded startup based in Dublin, Ireland. The are working on a health sensor product to combat back pain. I have worked for them as an iOS Developer to develop a prototype app to communicate with the sensor using BLE.

Additive Flow LLC - Flectron Front End Freelancer

April 2018 - June 2018, London, UK

https://www.additiveflow.com/

I worked as a freelance for 3d printing startup Additive Flow, who are developing innovations in the 3d printing space. I was contracted to develop a cross platform Electron controller app which would communicate over serial with their intricate printing setup.

Education

Music & Media Technologies / Master's Degree Trinity College Dublin, Ireland

2015-2016

Graduated with a First Class Honors degree. Thesis project was on the topic of using radioactive material to make music. I built my own particle detector and used the detections of subatomic particles to create a piece of music.

Theoretical Physics / Bachelor's Degree *Trinity College Dublin, Ireland*

2011-2015

Graduated with a First Class Honors degree. My thesis project was on the topic of the intersection of quantum mechanics and music. Specifically on the work of Denis Gabor who developed a mathematical framework for treating sound like a quantum system, with sound represented as particles or wave packets instead of pure waves.

Leaving Cert / High School Certificate **Pobalscoil Corca Dhuibne**, **Ireland**

2005-2011

Graduated secondary school with a result of 590/600 points. In the top 2.5% nationally in 2011. I scored all As in Irish, Spanish, English, Mathematics, Physics, Engineering, Applied Mathematics and Music.